Guide to the John C. Lincoln Institute collection ARCH104
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
John C. Lincoln Institute collection
1963-1985, undated
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH104
1 Linear Feet (4 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Historical Note
According to its website The Lincoln Institute for Land Study is a resource for policy makers and practitioners. The Institute addresses issues involving the use, regulation, and taxation of land. The Lincoln Institute for Land Study was established in 1974 by the board of directors of the Lincoln Foundation, which had been founded in Phoenix in 1946 by John C. Lincoln, an industrialist originally from Cleveland.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains material concerning the Lincoln Institute and other related organizations.
Land reform; John C. Lincoln Institute; Woodruff, A. M. (Archibald Mulford), 1912-; University of Hartford
- Assembly proceedings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- China Today, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Land reform papers, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Land reform, 1966-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
- Lincoln Foundation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Lincoln Institute memorandums, pamphlets, and reports, 1966-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Farm policy statistics, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Tarkio assembly reports, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Woodruff, A.M., Circa 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Publications, 1963-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Territorial Conquest-Phillip and Afterwards, 1975 Aug (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents
    Else-Mitchell, R. Territorial Conquest-Phillip and Afterwards. Reprinted from The Victoria Historical Journal. August, 1975
  - Land Use in America: Report of the forty-fifth American Assembly at Columbia University, 1974 Apr (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Land Use in America: Report of the forty-fifth American Assembly, April 18-21, 1974.
  - The Lincoln Foundation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    The Lincoln Foundation: Founded by John C. Lincoln in 1947. 1963.
  - The Farm and the City: Final Statement of the New England Regional American Assembly, 1981 Apr (Box 1, Folder 14)
    The Farm and the City: Final Statement of the New England Regional American Assembly. Co-Sponsored by the University of Hartford Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station and The American Assembly. April 20-22, 1981.
  - 1966 International Seminar on Land Taxation, Land tenure and Land Reform in Developing Countries, 1967; 2 Volumes 2 copies (one paperback, one hardcover) (Box Shared Book Tray 3, Volume 0207303178140, Volume 0207303178157)
    Woodruff, Archibald M., James R. Brown, and Sein Lin. 1966 International Seminar on Land Taxation, Land tenure and Land Reform in Developing Countries. Sponsored by the John C. Lincoln Foundation at the University of Hartford, 1967.
  - Land Reform Implementation: a Comparative Perspective, 1974 (Box Shared Book Tray 3, Volume 0207303178165)
    Lin, Sein. Land Reform Implementation: a Comparative Perspective. John C. Lincoln Institute, 1974
  - Readings in Land Reform, 1970 (Box Shared Book Tray 3, Volume 0207303178173)
    Lin, Sein. Readings in Land Reform. Hartford, Connecticut: University of Hartford, 1970.
  - Real Property Taxation and The Urban Center, 1972 Jan (Volume 0207303178181)
    Smtih, Theodore Reynolds. Real Property Taxation and The Urban Center: A Case Study of Hartford, Connecticut. Hartford, CT: John C. Lincoln Institute, University of Hartford, 1972.
  - The Property Tax and Local Finance, 1983 (Box Shared Book Tray 3, Volume 0207303178199)
    Harriss, C. Lowell. ed. The Property Tax and Local Finance. New York: Academy of Political Science, 1983.
  - East Asian Agrarian Reform: Japan, Republic of Korea, Taiwan and the Philippines, [1970?] (Volume 0207303178207)
    Smith, Theodore Reynolds. East Asian Agrarian Reform: Japan, Republic of Korea, Taiwan and the Philippines. Hartford, CT: John C. Lincoln Institute, 1970.